all right today's video today I wanted
to talk about information I was going to
talk about something more complex and
I'm like okay we need to break this down
so that I don't want to talk about
something for 15 minutes information is
very powerful it's why we have in need
the want to say media that's wrong the
like news papers and the people who
report the news reporters that but that
even that has of course become an
entertainment industry and so we can
trust it less and less and you know that
that Trump is in all this all this fake
news business and but he has a point
it's hard to know what is true and what
is not but that's not exactly what he
say and he's like anything against me is
false we need to be able to have access
to information that we can trust where
we don't have to have the same debate
over and over and over again because we
can look at it and say is it true or is
it not true because even if you research
everything even if you're the best
researcher on the planet when you're
talking to somebody else policymakers
your cousin it Thanksgiving unless they
know the information it's not helpful to
argue with them like you're because they
don't necessarily trust your information
so having one database of information
that we can trust empowers us and
unleashes humanity's potential in a lot
of areas so what we need from
information as everyday citizens and
people is trust for the information we
need to know be able to know is this
trustworthy or not is it frumpy and
that's gonna be different for different
areas study like peer reviewed for like
science but also okay well why aren't
these things peer reviewed what is
missing from the peer reviewed journals
is also really important because that
brings the politics into it but as we're
able to understand and organize the
information I'm realizing I'm two
minutes in and haven't gotten very far
on this list of things to talk about we
need it to be organized the information
so that it's usable we need it to be
available to anyone who needs it and
that means it also needs to be
understandable
so if it's just a big database crap of
numbers that nobody wants to use then I
mean that can still empower people if
they know they have access to it and
it's trustworthy but it's not the same
as having infographics and having things
that can make it actually accessible to
everyone and we all benefit from that so
the areas that I want to have
information this isn't one big project
these would all be individual and
possibly dozens of individuals under
every heading health and science is a
huge one that's my area economics and
understanding the system of of trade and
and all of that history it's not my
strong point but I like storytelling and
time liens and to be able to see
visually what is happening politics what
our politicians say and do these things
are all out there they're public
knowledge but they're not organized so
we can't use it because we're gonna have
the same like Trump himself is like I've
said this I didn't say he argues with
himself like he'll say one thing and
then unsay it the next time the law
which I had actually looked that far
into like that's that we're wrong right
and goes because the laws can be change
but understanding the law the law is
written having that and then what that
means so that it's accessible to people
with the information available ready to
go that we've we have it you know it's
ten years in the future we have access
to these things people can invent and
create and discover new things much more
efficiently when we're not having to
read design that wheel every time you
don't have to start with ok so what's
all the information that's out there
because no matter what it is someone's
already compiled and if they haven't
then you can compile it make it
available for future people that don't
don't need to have it and making that
process easy and hopefully enjoyable so
that it's not a slog to get through the
information it's on a slog if you're the
first person there table to add - you
don't have to add absolutely everything
you have to add what you would need in a
way the algorithms help you figure out
is it trustworthy is it because we've
decided on those older video one of the
biggest things it does is release this
need
debate back before the internet was so
prevalent and IMDB was a thing although
I just looked it up and it's the 90s and
it was the thing so I was definitely
still having those debates but you'd
have a debate with someone about like
who starred in what movie what movie
came out when and try it now any party
you're at two minutes in someone's gonna
google it someone's gonna get to IMDB
and be like oh yeah like the there is no
debate it solves and that's what I want
to have access to for science for
climate change for health and like it's
never going to be that easy to look it
up because you're looking at all of
cancer research but like yes all of this
cancer research says that this is the
best course of treatment to be able to
have access to that same level where
it's not going to be a big debate
because it's it's right before you in
black and white and obvious grace the
things we can create with that
information once it's there or infinite
because it's up to the individual so
once if you're a writer and you're
writing during a period of history you
have access to everything that would
have been available at that time you can
even have it so that it will scan your
writing and say wait you put a clock in
here like a alarm clock that wasn't
available so till this time period and
the biggest thing is is that work done
by we don't have to keep reinventing it
we don't have to every person doesn't go
and have to go and research everything
it's about coming together on one topic
brainstorming what we want
deciding what makes it trustworthy and
then grading it to that trustworthiness
we don't get to debate and and discuss
whether we agree with it because the
biggest thing information gives us is
power against our own bias we all have
that gut feeling that thing it's like oh
no I don't agree with that but that
doesn't make it right or wrong it just
we need the actual truth once we have
the foundation of truth we can work off
of work off of that I think these are
all very important to have access to
however they are also partly because of
our mentality they need to be free and
available to everyone like Wikipedia I
don't think people will come in and want
to pay ten dollars a month to get
as to the information that's there like
Wikipedia oh it's free but this is like
Oregon all of the information and not
just in a Wikipedia article its grading
the science it's being able to see every
single peer-reviewed and what happened
in it and what like it's it's more
complex than Wikipedia but people are so
used to getting it for free that this
needs to be kind of amongst the ones
that people are like it's what we do
with this information that gives us the
power to charge ten dollars a month for
the apps
it's that with the the science
information we can bring that into the
doctor's office with us with the
economics information we can make better
decisions as communities and be able to
figure out our transportation system
something it's what we can do with that
information the next level that all of
the magic happens at that isn't
currently available this information is
available this is just about making it
organized and understandable and alright
that was today's video I could keep
going on and on and on about any topic
what do you like the time turns out so
so what happened it's in I will see you
tomorrow